

Email: krupeshved@gmail.com | Mobile: 98199 17577 | https://www.linkedin.com/in/krupeshved

Career Summary

Problem Solver | Product Enthusiast | Thinking Different

An enthusiastic learner with five years of international experience across the United States, Europe and Asia Worked in the Hi-Tech Semiconductors Industry with a passion to deliver world-class differentiating products

Professional Experience

ASIC Design Engineer at Apple Inc., Munich, Germany

Nov 2019-Mar 2020

Worked as a Feature Lead on cutting-edge wireless technology to power the next-generation Apple products Defined the cellular requirements, features and use cases in compliance with the latest 4G/5G NR standards Collaborated with the Hardware and Systems Engineering Teams during silicon tape-out and Chip Bring-Up

Senior Firmware Engineer at Intel Deutschland GmbH, Nuremberg, Germany

Jan 2018 - Oct 2019

Developed a power-saving feature, thereby saving 90 minutes battery life by optimizing the UE wake-up time Served as designated responsible individual for customer interaction & delivery during product launch phase Led several cross-functional teams across multiple geo-sites worldwide to drive end-to-end feature delivery

Software Development Engineer at Intel Corporation, San Diego, California, USA

Feb 2015-Dec 2017

Joined Intel as a recent college graduate working on LTE physical layer controller for Intel's Wireless Modems Contributed to Intel's \$4 Billion Cellular Business by implementing 3GPP physical layer algorithms in firmware Gained hands-on experience in embedded design and coding using C/C++/Python programming languages

Graduate Technical Intern at Intel Corporation, Chicago, Illinois, USA

Jun 2014-Aug 2014

Completed a summer internship as part of curriculum practical training at Intel's RnD Center in Kemper Lakes Automated a script in MATLAB to reduce the log analysis time by 50% thereby saving hundreds of man-hours Documented the system design specification which served as reference for the development and verification

Education

MBA (PGPX), Indian Institute of Management Ahmedabad

Apr 2020-Mar 2021

Currently enrolled in IIMA's one-year Post Graduate Programme for Executives

MS (Electrical Engineering), University of Southern California, CGPA: 3.87/4

Sep 2013-Dec 2014

Conducted directed research on WARP Radios with Ph.D. students at the ANRG Research LAB Teaching Assistant and Course Grader to students enrolled in the course EE 567 at USC

BE (Electronics and Telecommunications), Mumbai University, 82.5%

Aug 2009-May 2013

Top 1% in college. University topper across 73 colleges in Mumbai during third year of Engineering Volunteered for several activities and events at the college Cultural and Tech Fest

Certifications

MOOCs (Machine Learning and Artificial Intelligence), Coursera	January 2020
MOOCs (Transitioning to Product Management), LinkedIn Learning	November 2019
CFI (Accounting Fundamentals, Fixed Income & Corporate Finance)	November 2019
CFA (Passed Level One Examination), CFA Institute	June 2019
CORe (Credential of Readiness), Harvard Business School Online	September 2014

Achievements & Awards

Received a Divisional Recognition Award at Intel for improving the modem's power KPI by ~7% or 90 minutes Admitted into the prestigious MSEE Honors Program for doing outstanding research with the ANRG Group Top 1% among 1200 incoming students to receive the USC Dean's Fellowship Award (~\$5100 tuition waiver) Awarded the J.R.D Tata Scholarship twice during the second and third years of undergraduate engineering

Extra-Curricular Activities

Organized several volunteering events at work such as a diversity fair to contribute towards community service Managed league funds and team reserves for twenty-two teams participating in SDCA's cricket tournament Volunteered to teach English and Science to underprivileged children at Mumbai's Shindewadi Public School